[Music]
so where should we start should we start
with the Petersons eASIC debate and then
see where it goes from there I guess
this is the first time we have a Sweeney
versus part post she should versus
mm-hmm so what did you think of the
debate it was quite predictable
Savo won my handsomely but in a graceful
way and I hope to begin with they're
both more interested in each other after
the debate and I certainly think that a
lot of salvation fans out there are
going out buying Jordan Peterson looks
and there's certainly a lot of Jordan
Peterson fans out there who buy
obviously she's books so it's really we
get more dialogue between the two I mean
solid won in a way because he I think
you know quite early in the debate he
just said we'll come on this is not like
a fighting ring this is just like two
fighters in the ring this is we're
trying to have a civilized discussion
here you know if we don't want the boos
of the yet because and I think that was
really graceful I'm very clever in a way
that's where he won I mean if Shaw wish
it woulda won the debate you could just
have stood there and said you know the
the last asus tickets for this room
right now we're a thousand dollars a
person
mark says and wins over capitalism right
there you know there was a certain greed
involved with the whole event that's
just exposed to that you know it was a
bit of a red carpet event in that sense
which i don't think that was their
intention but it is it wasn't red carpet
event it was in their expense it to go
there was a privileged elite ii went to
that event so yeah that was problematic
but probably didn't so we didn't do stat
and I think he's more of a sport and he
was more interested in sincere things
like that Robin tried to make it a
fighting win the general problem is this
one Americans don't read Hegel uh-huh
they rarely do and that's why they get
things wrong and for example but when
when Jesus went it out you know
Fredric Jameson wrote the book
post-modernism in 1982 where he fiercely
attacked the real science it would the
current social justice warriors right
the Marxist have always attacked the
social dozens of others so how dare you
Lim Peters to speak speaking about
cultural Marxists or culturally Marxist
or whatever that means it's
nothing to Marxism he never did the
Marxist always hated the neuroscience
and social justice warriors to Marxist
is just petit-bourgeois
resentful little church ladies you know
the social justice words are no interest
to Marxist revolution whatsoever James
says this Dziedzic says this
Chomsky says these Alain Badiou says
this you know all the leading leftist
thinkers basically despise the social
justice warriors and and you know as far
as your the more Nietzsche left is bent
say little notions out there or or say
Simon quickly was good book always
brilliant or very neat you if you're
sort of making meat your left just as
well but then you just fight social
justice warriors even more so Jordan
Peterson's gotta to get a few things
right for now he's got it stop saying
cultural Marxist there are no such
things he says but just two he says
postmodern neo-marxist I guess that's
the same thing post marty why do you all
marks and marks is not to blame for
anything they say if marx had agreed
with no soul why the hell would Marx
have written any books to begin with
Rousseau was the dominant thinker of
Europe in the early 1800s so Karl Marx
came along he took Simon Hegel and he
then started doing Marxism essentially
and that was a huge reaction against
true soil isn't just like Hegel hated
Locke okay ego hated lock for locked up
for introducing the idea of the tabula
rasa like the the empty soul which you
can fill with anything yeah so log has
been the problem for liberals all along
Andros all has been the problem for the
so-called hero so I left all alone but
in reality Locke and Rousseau is where
this whole me no social justice warrior
starts running and bit concerned about
extension rebuilding going on at the
moment I agree that we need to save the
plan
extinction rebellion now they just
social justice warriors trying to find a
new calls full of themselves and even
more narcissist well do you think it's a
doomsday cult you know of some kind I
think it's a narcissism call
okay okay every guy seemed involved with
extinction rebellion tries to make a
personal sales pitch out of their
involvement Hey
you walk down the bridge in London
somebody who wasn't even you through a
colorful bump somewhere you know and and
and it made it into the media and nobody
was hurt it was not a rebellion he just
politely walked down the bridge to get
your damn Instagram picture and get your
name in there to look good you know
Hagel has a wonderful term for these
people who make such an effort and
looking good all the time he calls the
beautiful souls and he means that
sarcastically mm-hmm my version of that
is don't be bono I prefer you to be
rather than to be bono the extinction
rebellion again is just a social justice
or ism
they've lost their cause and if anything
the Sheikh vs. Peterson debate in
Toronto was the death of a social
justice worse they're still causing tons
of havoc at universities in academia in
Europe North America and the world for
years because it's the only place
they've got left but intellectually
speaking the social justice warriors
over and done with and I think even
Jordan Peterson gets it now but the
Marxist left the proper left the workers
left was always against the social good
if you read maps Amin yeah he's a good
but it's a messy book but it does have
quite a few great things in it is far
better than tolerance medicine meaning
at least as Peter Sellers best and he
still the good point was to fight good
needle
it is MIT sick he spent that his entire
life and I think if you've read
Nietzsche he has and the first thing you
do when you read an inch is you go
beyond good and evil at least a grown-up
nature the four mature own age should be
on good and he was neat just by far best
book of them all and they're all good
right yeah and and if you don't
understand what it means to be on good
maybe we still want to be the good
little boy fighting evil out there in
the world I mean you haven't done just a
beat you in that case maybe that is also
a ends up with Christianity repeatedly
because the other thing I'm asking
Jordan Peters and we've done that in the
past you and ice that he got he's got to
come out as an ironic Christian there's
a big difference between a proper
Christian ironic Christian a proper
Christian believes in the virgin birth
that it actually happened a proper
Christ
believes that Christ died on the cross
was dead for three days and the damn
corpse came in live again three days
later and a proper Christian believes in
the rupture their old incredibly
supernatural right they break all the
laws of nature that we no longer but
proper crisis believe those three things
deep happened when Carl Jung and car one
of Carl Jung's
he wasn't defending Christianity but he
thought the Christianity would help
people from becoming to hyper-rational
like that was part of its strength like
why it's to save people from the sort of
rational you know if Jordan Peterson
wants to be more honest stop accusing
Marxists of things that have nothing you
alerts number one it can make allies
among the Marxists who actually agree
with you on tons of things right just
because you were socialists in the past
I've never been a socialist and I'm
certainly communist and so was Marx the
big difference we could be a socialist
or a communist do you want to talk about
that and the second thing the second
thing here Jordan Peterson's gotta come
out as an ironic Christian I don't
believe that he believes the virgin
birth happened in either doesn't believe
that and so many of his followers go
straight into the Catholic Church and
believe even the virgin birth and
believe Jordan direct him there
that is so false and it's gonna just
gotta hit back at Jordan eventually he
better come out as ironic waste and make
it clear once and for all if he believes
in the resurrection or in the virgin
birth or all or just symbolically there
were important because it's a helluva
give me thoughts and mobile see that the
mythos is that these stories actually
there was a point to them they search
something fine but then you're not
Roenick Christian I'm sorry the Pope
would not welcome to the Catholic Church
not a single Protestant or you're a
heretic I mean I mean I mean that's what
his best friend Jonathan Biagio called
them he said you're a heretic and he's
an Orthodox Christian he said no
Peterson exactly okay but then Jordan
Peterson better come out because if he
cleared the air and got over those two
obstacles he could do amazing things but
he stuck with those talk
one of the thing I was thinking is that
he's an ease I was attacking ideology
and yet he has an ideology obviously
horsey he's been run by ideology that's
the whole point
people are run by ideology people are
possessed by ideology people ideologies
to have an ideology hopefully a branded
Christianity the way you did it is an
ideology I think Jordan Peterson son
Ronnie Christian I think it's a
Nietzsche a Freudian and Union well he's
an individualist that means he ends up
with Monell cont and the cart and I
don't but I've read it up and Hegel tore
cunt apart mm-hmm individualism died
already with Hegel it started with Hegel
in the early eighteen hundreds and
that's exactly what Marx came back and
we interpreted Hegel and started talking
about the proletariat which is like he's
dream of the ultimate triumph it's a
tribal ideology that's what I liked
about Lawrence isn't it Nietzsche then
tried to make a last attempt at saving
the conch an individual and again about
turning him into an aristocrat in the
ubermensch but still a guy out on his
own fighting the demons sound it's it's
still Christian in the sense that
Nietzsche's Nietzsche's ubermensch is
also the guy who goes out of the desert
and resists the temptation from Lucifer
which is the temptation to be resentful
he's the night as well or something like
that and yes that's fine but at the end
of the day where's the damn team people
on their own don't do anything about
history he teaches a perfect example of
that you've got to have a team you gotta
have you got especially it sit there
talking about happiness on some level
like yeah I mean nobody's happier on
their own right well at least they
killed her happiness I mean the theme
for the she succeeded event was just
pickable this is not happiness
capitalism versus smarts ISM to begin
with none of them defended happiness
none of them defended capitalism none of
the defendant Marxism yeah
didn't even defend Marcus he's like no
he said alien to begin with he admitted
that right because in the past and one
would have the one would think that he
would defend mercs no no no I have never
ever seen snobbish ishik say that he's a
Marxist he calls also I think he's an
ironic Marxist you're saying he you know
because he he does say the Marxist and
me you know in certain situations he
says in his book well the Marxist to me
it's not the same thing I can say the
Buddha saying I'm a Marxist no I agree
with you because I'm a hater you like it
yeah ok I'm a communist that means if we
can create the communist utopia and it's
widely available for people and they can
choose or they don't like you to join it
that's the return to the original tribe
communism to me is nothing but to return
to the sochi on the original nomadic
tribe that's not the communists I'm not
a socialist because I don't believe in
constructing huge welfare state
bureaucracies where the government
decide what kind of life you're gonna
live as what socialism is I'm so so the
problem with Peterson is individualism
and the problem with Z Zack is maybe uh
nostalgic for collectivism of some kind
no I don't think he's no I don't think
she I don't see she is nostalgic about
anything
he calls himself a pessimist can't you
choose a pessimist of being nostalgic it
doesn't long back for something that he
thinks will return I think pessimism is
sloppy just like I think atheism is
sloppy I don't think the pessimism is
the end of anything
I don't think atheism is the end of
anything I don't think liberal
democracies the end of anything I never
discuss what the future is good or bad
depends on who you ask
right okay if human beings make
themselves distinct or nuclear bombs and
climate threat or whatever that's good
news for cockroaches now to write a book
in defense of cockroaches that is the
lander wrote a book in defense of
viruses and bacteria it's certainly
optimistic about the future okay so it
depends on who you worst one of them all
these nuclear bombs
by far our worse than climate change
nuclear bombs we can't okay if nuclear
bombs set up on drones so these drones
are owned by the various sects and cults
have no control over it's gonna be total
haggle that's even likely to happen the
next 50 to 200 years yeah so we're gonna
need the machines we're gonna need the
machines and if the machines can teach
us how to love the stranger because we
can't do that alone we can go from
nation to empire that requires first the
nation works and number two if the
requires that we learn from industry you
created empires in the past that
consisted of nations mm-hmm that's why
I'm starting the person in price right
now I'm gonna write about them in the
next book because there were three
successful continues empires over here
to 1500 years that were all pluralistic
Imperial and then contained nations for
example the nation of Israel mm-hmm
that's a really good story that we can
retell today and say we can do this
again we can do better and it can last
longer this time because we have to
acknowledge this the person does never
had okay so you're saying wish it was
ideal wise they got it correct mm-hmm
so you're saying you're saying we have
to kind of in a sense integrate all
these things integrate the nation and
then yeah towards this global sort of
what you call a global Empire maybe you
want to clarify the concept of global
Empire because it's called it's called
the Internet right mm-hmm maybe he said
absolutely everything on our planet
today's being connected with everything
else so that planet becomes one huge
computer okay so the your argument is
not that this is going to destroy the
nation-state that but we that it's going
to be above the nation-state like we
have a kind of hierarchy empire nation
okay China Russia sort of experimenting
with somehow being outside of the
internet towel fail dictatorships of the
world to try to turn off the internet
two days later all the traders and those
is God in the streets ready to kill the
precedents and they have to put the
internet back on again there is no way
you can disconnect the world from the
internet in this sense our prophecy in
the book synthesis of creating garden
into the days has already happened God
is already here God is called internet
internet now controls the world
mm-hm it's one huge phenomenon because
it means that all computers and all the
smartphones in all the sensors and all
the data centers on the planet are
connected with each other and as soon as
you got a cloud of data in Word it's in
the interest of that cloud to unify
itself with other clouds of data so
eventually all these clouds data become
one huge cloud now if all data of the
world goes into one cloud and both
Google and the Chinese Communist Party
are attempting to do exactly that at the
moment as soon as you got one good
scholar that is all the data of
everything human beings do and
everything that happens around us mm-hmm
then that computer will be capable of
predicting the future on a level that
none of us none of the rest of us can do
and that includes predicting the future
of each one of us and it's groupings so
you can move all the way down to the
tribal level the Dunbar's number which
is a hundred and fifty seven hundred
fifty seven is the number where people
that we could connect with that most of
us could connect with we have have an
idea who they are if you know them you
know their names you know the
backgrounds about 150 separate people I
mean it's the entire tribe including all
elderly and children can be much wonder
50 people and it's the ultimate size
first we a program to handle that
that's easy we call that intra tribal
you don't have to teach a human being to
the intertribal that's easy to go
anywhere beyond that takes effort it
takes narrative takes priestly work so
the move from tribe to clan was the
first step the next step was climbed to
nation yeah it's taken us the last 3,000
years to move from clan to nation that's
that's kind of the story of the exodus
again or what we're going about
nationality so so nationalism so the
first one is the exit is our leader
Moses to the prom
land is the first nation ever know it
had 11 tribes in it the 12th tribe was
the Samana caste surrounding the other
level it's exactly our large tribal look
they should imitating the tribe would
look exactly like the nation of Israel
that's why the Jews are the ultimate
nationalists the nation of Israel is
beautiful and it's the beginning of
nationalism and ironic results at the
end of nationalism because the last
territorial expanding nationalist
project in history it's the State of
Israel today
that's scientism we succeeded we're not
just failed so that's it now Israel then
had a second Exodus and this time it
came out of an empire that set them free
the first Exodus was out of an empire
that had to flee from because it was a
collapsing Empire and that was the
Egyptian Empire run by little boy
Pharaohs to build pyramids the second
Exodus is out of Babylon
that's the Persian Empire the person
empires that is the good Empire that's
authentic Empire because sets the de
Deus free and Charles and go back to do
some builder temple and establish a
knight nation so that we can show all
the other nationalities really Empire
that we set nations free will allow them
to believe whatever they want to build a
long term that is too fundamental
understanding what religion reading is
and that understanding cause only one
religion that's a rest Ernest because
mr. Aston ISM possibly also Hinduism or
the old legends that have understood and
research for religion is rather makes
some empty claims some beliefs that are
taken out of context and therefore dust
that understand religion Christianity
never understood the phenomenon and the
religion because otherwise Christianity
would look the way does none of the
Abrahamic faiths have understood
religion because if they understood
religion they would never have gone
banal stick and do it it was a big
mistake
they were never gone Gnostic in
dualistic so the truth the two religions
are non non-dualistic no I say monastic
monastic I don't know where that word
non-dualism comes from why did you say
non-dual when you can just say monastic
so I'm a radical be
list mm-hmm and what I like about
Aristotle as the opponent of Plato is
that he's a realist too and I think the
realist tradition starts or start with a
moves forward through Spinoza and we end
up with the last today the idea of
realism is that it's perfectly feasible
for us to have a connection with the
world around us and we have to I mean
the danger always starts we try to
imagine that we somehow are removed from
from reality and the big mistake that
was done in the West was the idea of
dualism and it starts with Plato and and
of course Judaism has the problem Islam
and Christianity certainly have this
problem we dualism right so the world
isn't dualist the world is modest so to
begin with it's a lie you know spirit
and body are not separate spirit and
body need each other they can be no
spirit without body into certain extent
that could be no body without spirit as
well so spirit about our United the one
thing being human is meaning having a
spirit and body they're just two
different attributes of the same
substance which is getting human so the
world is bonused
radically modest and and in there's just
one universe period and everything in
this universe is interconnected with
everything else the rest is just there's
an enormous amount of attributes that
it's just one substance Espino success
so that means the question is where did
dualism come from and I know the
conviction that dualism wasn't just an
idea that somebody that planar come up
with I think dualism has to do with the
child's fascination with a sexual ritual
the OI deepest complex right we are not
invited to section ritual women kids we
just know that dad's fucking mom men are
fucking women and we don't have the big
dicks and the process they have so we
cannot enjoy the pleasure they enjoy
meaning they love something more than
they love us that's the oil personal er
to conferences right now the section
ritual is the ritual religion and
sexuality are always intertwine with
each other there are only three arenas
in the tribe there's the battlefield
there's the campfire at night
and the third one is the ritual I mean
it's religion and sexuality should be
united because religion is how we messed
agates sexuality to serve the interests
of the child mm-hmm oh it's interesting
in you know in Hinduism their United
because they're going to achieve a
temple in India and they got Fowler's
his every word you can go into call the
temple and and she's the goddess of
chaos which is the perfect miniature
meaning that behind me there's only
chaos
do you know terrified of me and move
ahead of me you're gonna die and the
chaos going this way always a metro the
metro to the patriarch are there in full
effect that's an Indian sense so as to
listen does the same thing interesting
anarchic parallel Ubud ism because
they're asterism takes on the
patriarchal role of leading the tribe
it's obsessed with the family in person
is called hoon are by the way that's a
personal word for that and who not a
mouth in in person means art everything
that comes out of the father's out of
the phonic is artistic aesthetic that's
a person idea it's very surest in the
other end is the Buddha and the Buddha
is really the worship of the metric like
why don't we just resigned to the chaos
that comes after us and then we're
falling into Nirvana which is okay
it's a perfectly acceptable in sexual
position the Chinese then tried to unify
these two that's called Taoism and then
of course it's a beautiful idea because
Taoism really is the religion of the
tribe the only problem with Taoism when
you place it inside a very advanced
civilization it's that it becomes an
obsession with harmony balance in the
irony here is that the Chinese maintain
harmony balance each time for about 150
years and then all of China in clothes
into massive blood baths as the entire
history of China looks like that and I'm
beginning to come to the conclusion that
maybe it's a good idea to worship
getting and young at the same time yeah
well I wish I remember I went to the
museum Ghibli and
in Paris and and you saw these Buddhist
statues and they were all they're all
very serene and kind of calm and
beautiful and harmony and then then
there's a tantric statues which this
energy this explosive energy you know of
the the
actors and their fierce and they have
skull cups and they're you know there's
this fierce energy that and that was
sort of wiped away in the 12th century
has this completely disappeared and and
and the religion became very let's say
very tame this this fierce kind of I
guess tantric energy which was always
they still build such samples in India
way into the 15th century but yeah they
were your first by Salaam and certainly
by Christianity and and they said you
have a a skeleton with asceticism up
this is the boys revenge on the
grown-ups it's just like no I'm not
gonna be like that I'm not gonna be
dirty like that I'm not gonna immerse
myself in sexual acts at all I'm gonna
stay above that and this is where the
good Gnostic starts in history and Plato
is of course he did par excellence you
know the ultimate agnostic it's just
like it's just like I am a boy and above
the grown ups and I can dream about
perfection I could dream about
immortality I can do about infinity
although none of those things are
actually exists because I'm a duelist
and I own spirit above body the body's
dirty and sinful but the Spirit is high
and clean and pure mm-hmm and when you
think about it this is the ironic
religious because they all came out of
Egypt they all come out of this fantasy
I always said that Plato is the Egyptian
grid it takes on Egyptian heritage it
takes the grace that is fatalism and
that is exactly a play to listen and the
Abrahamic religions have control what we
call the West mm-hmm and I think the
West in a way is a failed West because
the West should have been the Persian
Empire the Roman Empire and the Arabs as
a brilliant third new force but that's
what happened because be songs and
Stacia for these songs is to calculate
the new Rome and Stacie for us to
capital the Persian Empire where it's
such loggerheads with each other in
seventh century and it basically fought
each other to the ground and open up the
world for the Arab invasion and within
50 years of taking on half the planet no
I don't think the Muslims even had the
attention of expanding that rapidly that
that was but they did they did expanded
all the way to China all the way up into
northern
rustling they were way up into Europe
almost in Paris before they got stopped
they were all of course later on it's
all the way up to Vienna and eventually
they took all of us Africa and the
Middle East and large parts of the world
and they're now becoming so this Arabic
invasion that only took about 50 years
was a massive military victory but it
was the result the Persian Empire the
Roman and part of fighting he started
down to the ground so they were
incredibly vulnerable and what happened
was the Persian Empire became extinct
the sore aster is more or less
disappeared and became a small minority
religion and an Iran after that whereas
it started and of course Islam been
adopted tons of stuff from celestial
cultures for hundreds of years all the
famous Arabs were really well educated
persons right but the Persian Empire was
taken over by the errors and and of
course the persons have already moved
their capital to Stasi farm and all the
Arabs needed to do was to just move
their capital slightly west of
Statesville where they built Baghdad and
for the next 500 years back there was
the biggest city on the planet so there
are three babylons close to each other
babbling self steady phone and baguette
okay three-year which cost for Politan
cities all built in contemporary rock
with the Erawan baghdad was the last one
that we still have today but I think the
West should have been so asterism
because there asterism came from the
east so asterism never divided between
religion and sexuality
the Soraa askance considered the
manikins and the Gnostics to be totally
heretics they went after the master
kists the master case were the first
socialists or duelists they went after
the Gnostics and they went after the
manikins and they all considered it
through the radix worth your death
because the Soros no religion preaches
unity of religion and sexuality and it
does so exactly like thousand a Buddhism
and Hinduism dude because what's the
difference between that and Rousseau and
sort of romanticism Oh sick you know
sexuality and you know what's the
difference there Oh all but the result a
result on ISM is completely doing it
it's completely dualist I see no Woodrow
sergeant says that you can walk around
and fuck
anything you like whatever you like
you're free you know that so just
lacking in sophistication and ritual and
and that's that's not any better I'm
saying is that religion and sexuality
must be combined religion is how we came
sexuality in the service of the tribe
okay so we give it the energy to tab we
thrive on it we also put it in our heads
and we create civilization or amazing
things you can't just fuck anything like
those but you you must fuck because if
you don't you become a Catholic priests
too becomes a pedophile now the
pedophilia pandemic in the Catholic
Church today there's no such thing in
the Buddhist congregations there's no
such thing as arrestor ism there's no
such thing in Taoism it's exclusive in
the Catholic Church that the massive
pedophilia pandemic precisely we call
the Catholic Church is preaching that
sex outside of marriage and even outside
of marriage outside of and reproductive
purpose is a sin it isn't that's only
because the Catholic Church is full of
little boys who hate sex it always has
been and that has always been its
problem and now in care physicians with
these the religions this just has to go
do a listen is the one thing that was
testing in Oakland because doing is a
does not work and thankfully Western
philosophers from Hegel and forward have
worked intensively in constructing a new
Western bonus world from Hegel through
tunics one starts with Spinoza there
Hegel and Nietzsche and certainly whiter
than 26 trillion dollars we have this
rich now modern philosophical tradition
which is modest
you're saying that Peterson is a
Peterson is Peterson is either an
itching or a Christian you cannot be
both you can't
I wanted to come out and express is a
Christian or any Jew
you can't be both Lisa would be totally
totally posted that idea nice is the
reversible Christianity
he's Christianity inside out well he
called himself the Antichrist didn't he
exactly do you can't get away with it I
mean maybe you can't if you write 12
rules for life but not if you're serious
damn philosopher and political activist
if you draw oh you can't be serious
about that you have to make a stance and
and God I don't understand and we
arrived at a modest worldview and
physics agrees with us on this one
biology grease with us in this one
science grease with us on them on as
well you the east always got that right
and they got it right not because there
was scientifically superior but because
they never did split religion and
sexuality in the first place hmm this is
Freud's point to this is John's pointer
none of them are Christians so I don't
understand what Peter says playing this
game with his wealthy Christian churches
the North America that even want to be
popular with him or something I don't
know well as to me he's a really ironic
Christian and he should be what to me is
a Jungian I mean that's I think he's I
think he's a disciple of young that's
that's my theory i'm i think mostly
that's where he gets his you know
psychoactive power you know from reading
young and just my experience in reading
young i think that's where it comes from
yeah but like you know just a job like
you know it's it's it's so heretical and
quite a lot of New Age garbage in yo for
God's sake you can't just accept you
only 100 percent he was mad parts of his
life too it's just like he's like when
we talk about there is to tell you
revived and I'm all for you can't accept
everything Irish talking thought and
said some of these ideas are dead wrong
yeah but yeah but Young is so complex
that I feel that he's he feel like he's
misunderstood or he's the darker aspects
of him are misunderstood like people
have run away with the lighter aspects
of him and well you and I haven't
do we have a problem shadow of no didn't
believe in Gordon even know what would
that be a problem
I think if June if people are probably
doing this because you got a problem
with himself he wasn't coherent a lot of
things wrong great thinkers are either
coherent and have a system or they are
gold mines so you can find these he's a
gold mine yeah that's so because it's a
pioneer so so people haven't fully you
know figured him out yet I mean yeah he
has a gold mine that's that's how I
would look at him I mean yeah we've
we've had young Texan only published in
the last ten years so there's still tons
of stuff to research and dig into him
there's an old young this a young this
is often instigated thinkers too so yeah
it's a gold mine but that means to say
you're a young it means you probably
need to say you're something else as
well because you're not actually go hand
with with the specific system you don't
have a specific ideology at the end of
the day Jordan wants to take the next
step and serious about two things he
needs to do he needs to become an ally
with the Communists in the Marxist and
get over his childhood bad memories or
socialism we're not talking about social
justice warriors here oh oh she she is
totally posting them right sees another
the second thing is okay Jeff any holy
look that would happen I mean I mean
he's built his platform on a you know
very fierce you know well I've still
have problems with this individualism
but I have the problem with every
American I meet because Americans are
Cartesians
they got stuck with the mono comments
well you're saying he has to do this yes
to become you know yesterday yes sir la
with the Marxist and communist but I
find that very unlikely we could get
down to the Heritage after a model come
because the Americans in analytical
philosophy study continent you study 50
and there and you completely drop up in
Hegel arrives analytical philosophy
starts with the tragedy of not
understanding Hegel that's interesting
mmm-hmm I'm totally with him America
still produced really shining thinkers
in the worlds of semiotic some process
and complexity Charles Saunders purse is
one of them Alfred North Whitehead no
one but he did read Hegel and they did
understand him and they would
been impossible without hetero mm-hmm
they're American who get into light that
goes a person that goes white it that's
exactly what the brilliant the rest of
analytical philosophy in America and the
UK completely obsessed tiny little
issues so they could go under their
little academic dinners and still be
flirting with some women and be popular
as if they were some kind of little
scientific field philosophies not
assigns analytical philosophers in
America and be okay we're not gonna have
much use for them in the future because
all they did was sit around and divide
back and forth about tiny little details
like a little church ladies could have
done it besides a thousand years ago and
I didn't get anywhere it was not useful
there I mean any damn computer scientist
at least shit out of analytical
philosophers they're not they're useful
because they don't deal what philosophy
should we just metaphysics epistemology
phenomenology ethics and you know that's
shit no no they do sitting there you
know staring out their navels or
something trying to get laid or whatever
but they're not interesting and the
school the great schools of American
thinkers today like Adrian Johnston
Aaron sister Monell de Landa all my
favorite North American philosophers
today from one of them belongs to the
analytical philosophical school the term
in the back sonnet educated themselves
in Europe belong to the European
traditions and that's what the great
things I understand Hegel understand
lock on and it's like Freud certainly
get you yeah they got all those lazy
thinkers that your producer last studies
after hegel hegel made a turn after a
mono account well I think we believe we
live in the beginning of an egg alien
era that started in there are the
eighteen hundreds in terms of think he
was certainly doing I think the Hegelian
nation is what we did accomplish it's
the modern nation-state in Sabo's
fantasy so he said this would work and
he copied it after Napoleon's army he
did that in Furman ologists buried 1807
so you basically dope the modern nation
state or Hegel
we haven't done together in religion yet
that I would love to do how again we
have
Haga has an amazing understanding of God
which is exactly like a good his concept
of God from so you know can you see
something about that I'm curious what
Hegel's understanding of the absolute
has to be understood as a concept it's a
pure concept it's a name okay it's a
name it's a name of the earth father in
the tribe it's the name of the motor in
the track it's the name of the father of
the fathers it's the name of the mother
of the mothers it's the name of the
direction we're going
he's the name of the history we're
coming from meaning anything that has
value to us here now is God in the
future or God from the past that's a
girl in religion too that means the
original travel agent was a given so
this is all about a return to that
religious what would be the equivalent
to doing that today while we
postmodernist and we heard that we must
not have a grand narrative because
they're dangerous well that's the most
dangerous position a lot again that is a
grand narrative itself an anti narrative
that's really dangerous no no no human
beings need direction we need purpose we
need and that's all about where we're
heading next
well the extinction rebellion I want to
bring that up again because that seems
to be an anti grand narrative of some
kind
exactly that's exactly why so attractive
to the guy super so only two years ago
it's the same people it's sort of
powered aggressive isn't it it's like
exactly and it's not about solving a
problem it's about keeping the problem
it's about having an excuse to run
around being high yourself cuz your
extinction rebellion people like and all
of the most amount drug addicts and all
kinds of things they don't have careers
they don't have education they their
lives are miserable they're failing
they're getting resentful and suddenly
great time Iguchi comes along this
little Swedish girl I call the great I'm
Iguchi cuz you'll be out next year she's
just in for a season they're all playing
with her and then suddenly got the
extinction rebellion and it's like that
name in itself speaks volumes yeah it's
a fucking death worship its death
worship yeah that's right it's dystopian
yeah well I said I called it the
doomsday cult
you know yeah where are the solar or
wind power engineers when we need them
yeah exactly yeah good we don't need
these soulful fold Instagram narcissist
to say they're doing extinction
rebellion and protesting because we need
to save the planet nothing solid
anything
get a fucking education solve problems
like a fiction fusion power you know
it's just like if you solve the cube
problems would be kind of cheap reliable
sustainable energy on this planet for
the next 100 years we've solved
everything I think we I think it's also
I think they want to worship children
it's like they want to worship children
like like and this is the spirit of the
devouring mother or something it's like
they want their children who you've
refused to grow up it's the Virgin Mary
and the Jesus child all over again
without the father without the sound
without the gold like all the ghosts or
anything it's just the Virgin Mary Jesus
worship although again is the worship or
the mother of the child
they've already mother and a child that
refuses to grow up this is also going to
become the Gnostic extinction of billion
people are also oh it's Gnostic it's a
noise hates Gnostic heresy in fact isn't
it exactly they want the problem solved
they're not problem solvers anybody
anybody is utopian person will have a
problem they want to solve and they have
a method for solving that that's what
ideology is I want to create the
communist society and I won't do it by
giving human beings the chance to
collaborate the machines to solve human
beings from themselves and the problem
is not the climate threat the problem is
climate balance the question should
really be how do you avoid the next Ice
Age because if we're going to stay ten
billion people who responded we cannot
afford the next Ice Age yeah well you
said that for so it's it's kind of yeah
so we need to find technological
solutions to cultivate the planet it's
entirely so we can control it so we
could be ten billion people on this
planet for the foreseeable future
nothing else counts nothing else is
realistic nothing else nothing else is
interesting here and anybody claims
they're here to do anything else
probably on their own egotistic
narcissistic agenda meaning they're
enjoying the doomsday cult and they
enjoying the celebrity and prominence to
get from it and belonging to this this
anti tribe that they belong to it's a
sect it's a call to do thing called it's
not healthy doesn't it doesn't respond
to the needs of humanity it does it it's
childish infantile self Calculon
why don't I why do I see tons of
engineers working in these in these
extensions no I don't know I just see
tons of people who are hiring themselves
usually failed artists take tons of
psychedelics and they're very high in
themselves and walking in these trains
walking in these demonstrations together
be kind themselves like if they're
superior to the rest of us it's just the
same damn social justice warriors all
over again now they're just hijacking
the climate issue because they lost the
gender Wars yeah and they want to be
they want to be cutting-edge yeah yeah
it's all about being in and out
expression about fashions and fads
fashions and fads it feels that way d
yes nothing there's nothing sincere in
it it's not realistic it's not tied to
realism it's not tied to really okay the
void of it it's infantile and
self-obsessed the narcissistic Instagram
them meaning they're there at the
extinction our battle to get a picture
of themselves at a t-shirt and then they
go home three days later and nothing
will go change
yeah well just don't be innocent will
not win anything anyway you have to be
utopian to win anything and the only way
I love engineers I love engineering I
love to I teach engineers all day long
actually I don't them - they're creative
than they like wacky things and they're
you know yeah they work together on
weird projects and I love the makerspace
movement I love when kids sit and work
with their own hands and do funny little
technology things and invent their own
toys and things and I think to put stuff
into the hands of kids today with
technology tied to it so they work with
like intelligent toy material it's great
we need to get the kids off the screens
and we need to get them all
this idea that if they're at a screen
and they're talking writing on the
screen they have power and influence and
they should deserve attention just
because them there
oh that's important Jesus that would
Instagram narcissism is the technology
sauce makes it thrive and the
disappointment on these guys when they
realize that they just have liked each
other and hugged each other for being so
brave and wonderful and beautiful to
walk in the extension rebellion
demonstration then do nothing else
besides that this is just like this is
just like people signing things online
like they press a button anything
they've done something it's the same
attitude it's not about it's not about
solving the acute problems and in
climate right it's not that your problem
it is a problem but climate balance is
the real problem and containing nuclear
weapons is the other big problem those
are absolutely cute problems we need to
solve and if we don't solve them I hope
the machines solve them for us
and if we don't solve them and then
machines don't solve them it's not we're
done yeah this is just a crowd all over
again and if you ally yourself with that
crowd you're not gonna solve any
problems at all you're only there to
look great and get a t-shirt Instagram
picture a few likes nothing will happen
now if you're seriously interested in
say avoiding the climate threat today
you become an engineer and you know what
you probably build nuclear power plants
that's the honest truth
that's the honest scientific truth if
you want to avoid the nasty use of
fossil fuels in the world you want to
save Tibet for China
you want to save Himalaya for India you
want to save the Alps for Europe over
saying you wanna sell you want to sell
them
America the western half of you USA
because he's drying out and you want to
save the Middle East probably the part
of the world with much damage will be
done through the climate change is gonna
be the Middle East okay you want to save
those parts for the planet you're really
serious about that nuclear power today
is by far the most affordable best and
safe a solution you can have because
nuclear power minimizes
fossil fuels an absolute zero solar
power and wind power are not nearly
enough to compensate for that and
without cheap electricity we cannot do
what we need to do
anything else you say right now it's not
serious it's not it's not it's not
attached to reality it's just religion
it's just bad religious religion yes I'm
gonna cut open I think we can build a
sustainable planet
I think engineers can do that I'm
sincere Ethan echo Tokyo that's a great
word but I'm not an environmentalist
because the word environmentalism has
been oh great yeah with this horrible
nonsense that has nothing to do with
saving the planet or saving the climate
or anything I mean for God's sake why do
I have to put stuff in five different
bags every time I'm gonna throw away
some damn garbage
if artificial intelligence cannot even
help me put my garbage in the right
garbage bin then these bins there are
not about saving anything these bins are
only there to make people look good and
have other people look evil that's yeah
moralism and what another word I learned
from one of your books was Deema
demonism I think was the word you used
demonology yeah demonology it seems
objectification creating adages creating
you can get you can get away with the
lifestyle you haven't look good you know
there are people who love to have the
apartment next to the garbage bins of
the house so they can look out every day
and check who's doing what the cold
church-lady
and I think the church ladies next are
gonna walk in extinction rebellion
parades with tarot cards and do
astrology I'm probably gonna be next
cuz once you're this high yourself in
this lunatic in this devoid of you know
reality when you do these things you
might as well have the turn of cards in
astrology we didn't think that's gonna
solve anything
yeah I've got I've got more respect for
for the tarot current and the astrology
because it's a game right I mean it is
for the people to do it it's dead
serious and it's on the par with the
people who walk and extension rebellion
parades to look great in reality they're
not doing much at all you know it's just
that won't make a change that one will
make a difference right now I think that
you're a crowd
and engineers are much better at solving
the problems we have than any of these
people find themselves in Instagram
mm-hmm environmentalism is all my thing
at all but it could tokenism guess what
I believe in building the solutions oh
that's great you know I really I really
appreciate that I like I'm I'm so fed up
with the truisms and you know the
cliches and the you know everything you
all these words that people use and then
they just they I'm glad you're finding
new words for it you know where we need
to go yeah absolutely so I think it's
great that the kids are buying shoes you
can Peterson books and and the debate is
extended II if they didn't needs to be
more voices in there I don't think she
Shakur Peterson will never become
futurologist and this is about the
future
so where as making crate foundations and
hey she is absolutely right about we
need to read Hegel again the only issue
I really disagree with jiseok and I very
strongly is I find he is anti-semitism
towards Israel to be quite honest about
he's taken side with the sort of and
relating sort of a Western very petty
bourgeois Lobby which to me as much is
incompatible with the rest of his
philosophy he's chickened out on that
one
and place into something quite mean and
asked why would he suddenly be so
concerned with territory
I love Israelis and Palestinians I think
they're by far the two most interesting
and fascinating people in the Middle
East I don't know what the rest are lose
but that's that's my attitude why don't
we keep this attitude of being the
Buddhists of the semester who feels
superior to all these petite little
Westerners and they're they're citizen
religions